TAKRIM RAHMAN ALBI

Data Scientist | Software Engineer

- takrim.rahman.albi@g.bracu.ac.bd
- **J** +880-1625212429
- Mirpur-12, Dhaka- 1216, Bangladesh
- takrim-rahman-albi.github.io/





EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Go Zayaan

March 2020 - Ongoing

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Mentor | Code Quality Assurance

DeepLearning.ai

August 2021 - Ongoing

Remote, United States

Mentor | Data Scientist

Omdena

April 2021 - Ongoing

Remote, United States

Data Scientist and Python Developer

Codeware Limited

August 2020 - March2020

Dhaka, Bangladesh

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Member at youth Moch Parliament (2016)
- Design For Change (BRAC University RS Activity)
- Conducted various AI and ML workshops in *Data Science For Good* community

PROJECTS

Data Science and AI Projects:

Paraphrase Tool Using Neural Machine Translation

Alvi-Rahman/Paraphrase-Tool-NMT

Omdena- Road Safety in Bangladesh

OmdenaAl/omdena-bangladesh-roadsafety

Deep Learning Projects (DeepLearning.ai)

Alvi-Rahman/Deep-Learning-Coursera—deeplearning.ai

GAN Projects

Alvi-Rahman/GAN-Specialization



PROFILE

Having a curious mind and always willing to learn, I am an enthusiastic Data Scientist who is ready to take challenges and provide something state of the art using my skills and expertise not only to the Science community but also to the business domain.

EDUCATION

BSc. in Computer Science and Engineering

BRAC UNIVERSITY

2016 - 2020

Dhaka, Bangladesh

CGPA - 3.54 out of 4

SKILLS

Programming

- Strong Knowledge In Data Structure and Algorithms
- Experience in Programming Contest
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking

Data Science

Experienced in:

- ML and DL algorithms from scratch
- Data Pre-processing, creating Data and Model Pipelines, EDA, Graph Analytics
- DNNs, Computer Vision, Sequence, Attention and Transformers models, GANs
- Hyper Parameter Tuning and Optimization
- Specialized in Deep Learning Frameworks such as Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Trax
- Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NetworkX, OpenCV, Pillow, SpaCy, NLTK, Nilearn, Hadoop and Spark
- Deploying AI models

Development

- Django, Flask, React, Node, Bootstrap
- RESTful APIs, Serializers, DRF
- All social app authentication/authorization, GraphAPI, social permissions and apps
- Mysql, MongoDB, Postgres, Firebase
- Docker, Git, Nginx, Apache, AWS

Natural Language Processing (Coursera)

Alvi-Rahman/Natural-Language-Processing-Specialization

Computer Vision Projects

Alvi-Rahman/Computer-Vision-with-OpenCV-and-Python Stanford Machine Learning (Coursera)

Alvi-Rahman/Coursera-Machine-Learning-Andrew-Ng

Tensorflow in Practice (Coursera)

Alvi-Rahman/Tensorflow_in_practice_Coursera

Self Driving Car Projects

Alvi-Rahman/Self-Driving-Car-Specialization

AI for Medicine Projects

Alvi-Rahman/Al-for-Medicine-Coursera

Natural Language Processing Projects

Alvi-Rahman/NLP—Natural-Language-Processing-with-Python

Python Data Science (Scikit-Learn and ML)

Alvi-Rahman/Python Data Science and Machine Learning

Development Projects:

Go Zayaan Backend

gozayaan.com

All Social Media Under One Platform

idesk360.com

Tech Review Site

www.gsmriders.com

Some Other Mentionable Projects:

CAT-Chain : A Blockchain Based Categorical Information Transaction And Depository Framework

Alvi-Rahman/CAT-Chain

Some Solutions for Online Judge Problems

Alvi-Rahman/Programming_Contest_Problem_Solve

PUBLICATIONS

 Honorable Mention Award ACM CSCW 2020: Learning from Tweets: Opportunities and Challenges to Inform Policy Making During Dengue Epidemic. Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact. 4, CSCW1, Article 065 (May 2020) DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3392875

ACHIEVEMENTS



1st Runners UP (MUJIB BORSHO IT CARNIVAL 2020- DIU)

View Certificate

CERTIFICATIONS



Deep Learning Specialization

View Certificate



Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) Specialization

View Certificate



BIG DATA Specialization

View Certificate



Self-Driving Car Specialization

View Certificate



TensorFlow Developer

View Certificate



Al for Medicine Specialization

View Certificate



Stanford Machine Learning Coursera

View Certificate



Natural Language Processing Specialization

View Certificate



Al For Everyone





AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native

View Certificate



BIRDS Workshop

View Certificate

REFERENCES

Prof. Sriram Chellappan, Ph.D

- @ University of South Florida
- csee.usf.edu/~sriramc/

Prof. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, PhD

- Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology
- sites.google.com/site/abmalimalislam/